Moscow (Russia) • baltazar.bz@gmail.com • +79853037426 • linkedin • bitbucket • github

### **Summary**

Linux Python backend developer with 10+ years of experience in building, testing and maintaining complex software systems. 5+ years of Python experience, 6+ years of C++ experience, solid low-level background. Driven to get things done along with learning new skills, tools and technologies. Skilled to write efficient, maintainable and testable code. Able to communicate effectively and clearly in Russian and English both spoken and written.

### **Experience**

IPONWEB – media trading platform (RTB, Ad exchange, DSP, SSP)

Moscow

#### Senior Software Developer (Internal Tools, BidSwitch)

June 2017 – present

- Development of a user group update microservice (Python 3.4, pytest, pymongo, TokuMX)
- Development of a facade API service to an internal DB (Golang 1.8, Cassandra 2.6)
- Support of a log to DB loading tool (C++ 11, Cassandra 2.6)
- Development process: Scrum
- Technology stack: Docker, Jenkins, Artifactory, OBS, Graphite, Grafana, Kibana, Ubuntu 14.04

#### Senior Software Developer (Technology)

May 2016 – present

- Backend implementation of campaign visualization and forecasting service (Python, Django, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas)
- Software development process: Scrum + Kanban

#### **Software Developer (Technology)**

*July 2014 – May 2016* 

- Backend implementation of campaign visualization and forecasting service (Python, Django, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas)
- Participation in development of budget control server for advertising campaigns (Python, Twisted, Numpy, Pandas)
- Roll out and support of Continuous Integration infrastructure (Jenkins, Trial, pytest, custom testing stands)

### Software Developer (R&D)

January 2013 – July 2014

September 2009 – January 2013

• Support, development, and architechture refactoring of data delivery service (Python, BASH, Django)

SmartLabs – interactive digital television (IPTV, DVB, OTT TV)

Moscow

### **System Department Developer**

• Development of video content viewing redirector (C++, Qt)

- Development of video content distribution automation tool (C++, Qt)
- Integration of automation tool with existing platform
- Participation in SmartMedia platform video server development (C++, Qt, STL, live555)
- Implementation of adaptive streaming client (C++, Qt, Apple HTTP Streaming)
- Development of platform components build automation tool (Python)
- Participation in adaptive streaming server development (Python, Twisted)
- Accompanying protocols: HTTP, XML RPC, SOAP, RTSP

Autoscan Ulyanovsk

## Software Developer

September 2007 - May 2009

- Development of network applications for real-time video transmission (C++, Qt, OPAL, libjingle)
- Automation of application's testing (AutoIt, Erlang)
- · Accompanying protocols: XMPP, SIP, RTP, STUN

#### Ulyanovsk State Technical University

Ulyanovsk

### Technician

September 2006 – September 2007

- Computer class administration (11 computers, ASP Linux 9.0, Microsoft Windows 2003)
- · Class video surveillance organization, technical support

# **Education**

Ulyanovsk State Technical University	Ulyanovsk
Master's degree, Faculty of Information Systems & Technologies, diploma VMA 0105774	2007 – 2009
Bachelor's degree, Faculty of Information Systems & Technologies, diploma AVB 0512119	2003 – 2007

## **Additional Education**

Information Technology Alliance		coursera.org	
Clojure Course	April 2013	Machine Learning: Classification	April 2016
udacity.com	•	Game Theory (HSE)	March 2016
Programming a Robotic Car	April 2012	Machine Learning: Regression	February 2016
Artificial Intelligence	December 2011	ML Foundations: A Case Study Approach	February 2016
<u> </u>	December 2011	Cloud Computing Applications	October 2015
coursera.org	0 . 1 . 2012	Image and Video Processing	March 2015
Computing for Data Analysis	October 2012	Algorithmic Thinking	November 2014
Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part I	April 2012	Cryptography, Part I	June 2014
Machine Learning	December 2011	Write Like Mozart	March 2014
		Discrete Optimization	August 2013
		Functional Programming Principles in Scala	December 2012

## **Skills**

**Technical** OS: GNU/Linux (since 2009), Windows (2001 – 2009). Programming Languages: Python, C++. Moderately experienced as well in: Go, Haskell, Clojure, R, Scala, Erlang, Lua, AutoIt, Java, Octave, x86 assembler. VCS: hg, git, svn. Technologies: Unit Testing, Design Patterns, UML. Frameworks: Twisted, Pyramid, Django, Pandas, Scipy. **Language** Russian (*native*), English (*upper intermediate*).